Esther Jun Kim

drejkim.com

SUMMARY

I build products and proof-of-concept experiences. I also discover user needs, test with users early and often, and make informed design decisions from user data. I also create demos and hacks professionally and personally—they have garnered over 30,000 views on YouTube and nearly 300 stars on GitHub.

EXPERIENCE

Senior UX Engineer, Intel

Santa Clara, CA — Oct 2013 - Present

Designing experiences, conducting user research, and shipping products in the New Technology Group. Product influences include Edison, RealSense™, and Fossil O.

Senior UX Engineer, Samsung Research America

San Jose, CA — Jun 2011 - Oct 2013

Researched and designed next generation user experiences for Samsung products and services. Developed (and occasionally led) the UX analytics project for a multi-platform Samsung application.

Graduate Technical Intern, Intel

Hillsboro, OR — May 2009 - Dec 2009

Developed a test automation framework in C# and Perl to assess the media capabilities of Larrabee, Intel's GPGPU chip. Examined the usability of gesture interactions with laptop-mounted projector displays.

Electrical Engineer, Johns Hopkins Applied Physics Lab Laurel, MD — Jun 2004 - May 2007

Evaluated the infrared discrimination capabilities of Standard Missile-3 by processing and analyzing large-scale simulated telemetry and sensor data using Matlab and C++.

EDUCATION

Purdue University — PhD, 2011 Industrial Engineering (Human Factors)

Cornell University — MEng, 2004 Electrical & Computer Engineering

Cornell University — BS, 2003 Electrical & Computer Engineering

SKILLS

SW & HW Development

Languages: Python, Java

Web: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap,

AngularJS, Node.js, Jekyll **Mobile:** Android, iOS (Swift) **Hardware:** Edison, Arduino

UX Research

Usability testing, concept testing, surveys, UX analytics

Data Science

Information visualization, statistics, machine learning, R, Matlab, Octave

EXTRAS

3 patents filed 2 journal publications